Volodymyr Kniaziev

Senior Java Developer/Team Lead



Web: https://kniazievvolodymyr.github.io







Hi, my name's Volodymyr and I'm a senior Java developer, have 5+ years of commercial experience.

During that time I participated in different projects: fin-tech, gaming, resource managment, and ecommerce. I was involved in long-term projects which gave me strong experience in various areas of software design and development.

My primary interests now are connected with Java. I like programming, reading professional books, studying new technologies, and implementing them in my day-to-day work. I am always open to new and accept challenges with interest and enthusiasm. I have very good skills in problem-solving. I am open-minded and goal-oriented and have an active teamwork attitude and quick learning ability.

Experience

It's Europe's largest wholesale platform for used cars. More than 60,000 partner dealers in over 30 countries actively digitize their used car business with AUTO1 technologies and services. More than 500 microservice are running in production.

Auto1

Senior Software Developer/ Team Lead

may 2020 - Present https://www.auto1-group.com

Responsibilities:

Requirements analysis, Estimation, Prioritization, Design, Tasks distribution, Feature Releasing, Coordinating team activity, Server-side functionality implementation, Code reviewing, Bug fixing, Unit and Integration testing, Interviewing

Technologies used:

Java, Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Hibernate, Flyway, Maven, AWS, Docker, Redis, Postgres, Kibana, Grafana

It's a PAAS with customization capability for each customer's needs to be built on microservice

architecture. Customers can have different functionality for online/offline monitoring, diagnostic, and

prognostic of devices. All functionality was created from scratch with strong performance requirements.

Luxoft/DXC **Technologies**

Senior Software Developer/ **Team Lead**

september 2019 - may 2020 https://www.luxoft.com

Responsibilities:

Requirements analysis, Estimation, Prioritization, Tasks distribution, Coordinating team activity, Server-side functionality implementaiton, Bug fixing, Performance testing, Code reviewing, Unit and Integration testing, Interviewing

Technologies used:

Java, Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Design, Spring Security, Hibernate, Flyway, Gradle, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, Ehcache, Multithreading, Postgres, Ignite, Cassandra, JMeter, Grafana

Playtika

Software Developer

july 2018 - august 2019 https://www.playtika.com It is a bunch of online slot machines built on microservice architecture. Users can choose each of the slot machines and play, win coins or bonuses. To increase his game experience he needs to buy additional coins. All backend is based on Spring Cloud components, front-end is written on C# and includes Facebook and mobile clients.

Responsibilities:

Requirements analysis, Server-side functionality implementation, Integration with microservices, Code reviewing, Bug fixing, Unit and Integration testing

Technologies used:

Java 8, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Data, Maven, Guice, Couchbase, Kafka

PrivatBank Software Developer

may 2017 - june 2018 https://privatbank.ua

The biggest Ukrainian bank with its own development team provides powerful innovative functionality in fin-tech. I have been involved in the building of different services: online purchasing of gasoline, cards design, and funds transferring between accounts.

Responsibilities:

Requirements analysis, Server-side functionality implementaiton, Bug fixing, Unit testing.

Technologies used:

Spring, Maven, MyBats, Redis, Postgresql, MySql, Tomcat, JSP

Education

Ukrainian State University of Chemical Technology, Masters in Computer

2017 - 2019

2010 - 2015

Master Degree of Computer Sciences

Dnipropetrovsk **University of Economics and** Law, Masters in **Finance**

Master Degree of Finance